Michael Bourdeaux papers, Inclusive: 1958-2020, undated, Bulk: 1965-1996, undated
Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society
- Literary Works, 1958-2019, undated; 2
  - Book: Risen Indeed: Lessons in Faith from the Soviet Union: Reviews: Clippings and Correspondence (1 of 5), 1983 January-February (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Book: Risen Indeed: Lessons in Faith from the Soviet Union: Reviews: Clippings and Correspondence (2 of 5), 1983 March-April (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Book: Risen Indeed: Lessons in Faith from the Soviet Union: Reviews: Clippings and Correspondence (3 of 5), 1983 May-August (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Book: Risen Indeed: Lessons in Faith from the Soviet Union: Reviews: Clippings and Correspondence (4 of 5), 1983 September-December (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Book: Risen Indeed: Lessons in Faith from the Soviet Union: Reviews: Clippings and Correspondence (5 of 5), 1984-1985, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Book: May One Believe in Russia?: Reviews (1 of 2), 1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Book: May One Believe in Russia?: Reviews (2 of 2), 1981-1982, 1984, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Book: Christian Prisoners in the USSR: Keston College Staff Study: Reviews, 1985-1987 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Book: The Persecution of Christians in the USSR: Keston College Staff Study: Manuscript and proof, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Book: The Politics of Religion in Russia and the New States of Eurasia: London: M.E.Sharpe, 1995: Reviews, 1996, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Book: Proselytism and Orthodoxy in Russia: the New War for Souls: with J.Witte: Correspondence, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Book: Proselytism and Orthodoxy in Russia: the New War for Souls: with J.Witte: Orbis Books, 1999: Reviews, 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Book: The Religious Situation: Correspondence Pertaining to Contributing a Chapter, 1968-1969 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Book: The Religious Situation: Reviews, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Book: The Soviet Union and Eastern Europe: A Handbook: Correspondence Pertaining to Contributing a Chapter, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Book: The Soviet Union and Eastern Europe: A Handbook: Chapter "Roman Catholics and Uniates": Manuscript, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Book: The Decorative Arts of the Christian Church: by Gervis Frere-Cook: Correspondence Pertaining to Contributing a Chapter, 1967-1972 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Correspondence Pertaining to Contributing a Chapter, 1972-1975, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Chapter "The Russian Orthodox Church in Council 1945-1971": with Kathleen Matchett: Draft Manuscript 1, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Chapter "The Russian Orthodox Church in Council 1945-1971": with Kathleen Matchett: Draft Manuscript 2, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Chapter "The Russian Orthodox Church in Council 1945-1971": with Kathleen Matchett: Draft Manuscript 3, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Chapter "The Russian Orthodox Church In Council 1945-1971": with Kathleen Matchett: Draft Manuscript 4, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Book: Religion and Atheism in the USSR and Eastern Europe: Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Book: The Soviet Union Since the Fall of Khrushchev: Correspondence Pertaining to Contribution, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Book: The Soviet Union Since the Fall of Khrushchev: Chapter Manuscript, ca. 1975 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Book: The Soviet Union Since the Fall of Khrushchev: Macmillan, 1975: Reviews, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Book: Christian Appeals from Russia: by R.Harris and X. Howard-Johnson: Forward Manuscript, Correspondence and Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Book: The Soviet Union Since the Fall of Khrushchev: Royalty Statement, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Book: Persecution in the Early Church: by Herbert B. Workman: Forward: Manuscript, 1079 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Book: Persecution in the Early Church: by Herbert B. Workman: Oxford University Press, 1980: Reviews, 1981 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Book: You Did It for Me: by Roy Jenkins: Forward: Book Manuscript, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Book: Why Communism Failed: by George Weigel, ed.: Manuscript: Unpublished, 1992 March (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Book: The Meek and The Mighty: by Hans Brandenburg: Mowbrays, 1976: Introduction: Manuscript, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: Various Publishers: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1965-2018, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Sunday Telegraph: Manuscripts and correspondence, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: Soviet Studies: Clippings and Manuscripts, 1968-1975 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: Russian Review: Manuscript, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Times Literary Supplement: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1971-1984 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1965-1967 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1980-1983 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Clippings, and Correspondence, 1988-2017 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Catholic Herald: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1982-1983, 1992-1994 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: Canadian-American Slavic Studies: Manuscripts, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Tablet: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: The Times Higher Educational Supplement: Manuscripts and Correspondence, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Book Reviews: Journal of Ecclesiastical History: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1993-2017 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Articles: The Observer: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1960-1980 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Articles: The Observer: Correspondence, 1960-1977 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Articles: New Christian: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Articles: New Christian: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1966 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Articles: New Christian: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Assorted Articles: America: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1966-1972, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Assorted Articles: America: Correspondence, 1966-1975 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Articles: Problems of Communism [1 of 2], 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Articles: Problems of Communism [2 of 2], 1966-1972 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Assorted Articles: The Baptist Times: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1966-1984 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Assorted Articles: The Baptist Times: Correspondence, 1966-1973 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Assorted Articles: The Christian Century: Manuscripts and Clippings (1 of 2), 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Assorted Articles: The Christian Century: Manuscripts and Clippings (2 of 2), 1968-1971, 2000-2002 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Assorted Articles: The Christian Century: Correspondence, 1967-1972, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1964-1967 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1970 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1971-1972 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1975-1976, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1980-1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church Times: Manuscripts, Correspondence, and Clippings, 1988-2016 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Articles: The New York Times: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Articles: Liberty Magazine: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1979 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Articles: Survey: Manuscripts and Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Articles: The Guardian: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1975, 1991 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Articles: The Telegraph: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1967-1975, 1987, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Articles: The Telegraph: Correspondence, 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Articles: The Times: Manuscripts and Clippings (1 of 2), 1968-1992 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Articles: The Times: Manuscripts and Clippings (2 of 2), 1993-2017 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Articles: The Times: Correspondence, 1965-1977; 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Articles: The Anglican: Clippings, 1968 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Assorted Articles: Osteuropa: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1965-1974 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Assorted Articles: The Catholic Herald: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1968-1989 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Articles: Interlit: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1969-1979 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Articles: Forum World Features: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1969-1970 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Assorted Articles: The Reformation Review: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1969-1971 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Assorted Articles: Frontier Magazine: Manuscripts, 1970-1973, undated (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Assorted Articles: History of the 20th Century: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Assorted Articles: Congressional Monthly: Clippings and Correspondence, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Assorted Articles: Evangelical Times: Manuscripts and Clippings, 1971; 1985 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Assorted Articles: Life of Faith: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Assorted Articles: Catacombes: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Assorted Articles: The Atlantic Baptist: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1972-1974, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Articles: Eternity: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Assorted Articles: Guideposts: Manuscripts and Correspondence, 1971-1974 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Assorted Articles: Man, Myth & Magic: Clippings and Correspondence, 1968-1973 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Assorted Articles: Christianity Today: Manuscripts, Clippings and Correspondence, 1974-1982 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Assorted Articles: Southern Cross: Clippings, 1975-1977 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Assorted Articles: Life and Work: Manuscripts and clippings, 1977, 1988-1990 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Assorted Articles: Policy Review: Manuscripts and clippings, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Assorted Articles: The Catholic Register: Manuscripts and clippings, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Assorted Articles: The Tablet: Manuscripts, clippings and correspondence (1 of 3), 1965-1980 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Assorted Articles: The Tablet: Manuscripts, clippings and correspondence (2 of 3), 1982-1989 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Assorted Articles: The Tablet: Manuscripts, clippings and correspondence (3 of 3), 1990-1993, 1999-2003 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Assorted Articles: The Independent: Manuscripts and clippings, 1989-1991 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Assorted Articles: The Church of England Newspaper: Manuscripts and clippings, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Assorted Articles: Various Publishers: Published articles, manuscripts, and correspondence (1 of 4), 1962-1971 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Assorted Articles: Various Publishers: Published articles, manuscripts, and correspondence (2 of 4), 1972-1980 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Assorted Articles: Various Publishers: Published articles, manuscripts, and correspondence (3 of 4), 1981-1988 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Assorted Articles: Various Publishers: Published articles, manuscripts, and correspondence (4 of 4), 1990-2015, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Article: Religious Samizdat in the Soviet Union: with E. Voss: Het Christlike Olsten, 1974: Manuscripts, Clippings, Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Article: A Soviet Artist and Society: Arts Review, 1971: Manuscripts, Clippings, Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Article: A Criminal becomes a Christian In a Russian Prison: Translated: The Evangelical Magazine of Wales, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Article: Alexander Solzhenitsyn--Religious Writer: Ensign, 1971 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Article: Belief in God in Contemporary Russia: with K. Matchett: The Philosophical Questions Series: Manuscripts and Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Article: How They Teach the Faith in Russia: The Sunday School Times and Gospel Herald, 1974: Manuscripts and Clippings (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Article: Baptists in the Soviet Union Today: Baptist History and Heritage, 1975: Published article, manuscripts and correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Article: The Ukrainian Baptists: A Case Study In Soviet Persecution and The Resistance To It: with Roger Hayden: La Salle College: Manuscript, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Article: Dissent in the Russian Orthodox Church: The Russian Review, 1969: Clippings and correspondence, 1968-1970 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Article: Russia and the Church Today: A New Document from the Soviet Union: Eastern Church Review, 1972: Manuscript and clippings (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Article: Land of Crosses: The Church in Lithuania Today: Radio Liberty Research Paper no. 1, ca. 1975 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Article: The Protestant Churches in The Soviet Union and Eastern Europe: Societe Histoire Chretienne: Manuscript and proof, 1976 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Article: Chudi, kteri mnoht obohatili: Rozmluvy No 4: Clippings, 1985 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Article: The Church on The Eastern Front: The Oxford Companion to The Second World War: Manuscript, correspondence, 1992 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Article: Religion y religiones en Rusia hoy: Istor 2/2000: Clippings (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Article: Christianity In Russia: Continuum: Draft Manuscripts, 2003 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Article: The Orthodox Church and Communism: The Cambridge History of The Christian Church: Draft Manuscript, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries: Paul Anderson, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Obituaries: Father Alexander Men, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Obituaries: The Guardian: General (1 of 2), 1991-2000 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Obituaries: The Guardian: General (2 of 2), 2001-2007 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Obituaries: Various Publishers: General, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Obituaries: Father Gleb Yakunin, 2014-2015 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Obituaries: Irina Ratushinskaya, 2016 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Sermon: Witness on Trial in Russia: Great St. Mary's, The University Church, Cambridge, 1986 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Assorted Reports: The Right to Believe: Manuscripts, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Report: Sabbatical Report No I: Manuscript, 1981 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Assorted Reports: General, 1981, 1988, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Statement: The Sakharov Hearing in Copenhagen, Denmark, 1975 October (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Published Interviews: General, 1975-1987, 2015, 2018 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Video Interview: Revolution in Moscow, Thames Television: Contract, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Radio Interviews: General: Transcripts, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (1 of 6), 1968 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (2 of 6), 1971-1973 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (3 of 6), 1974 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (4 of 6), 1975 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (5 of 6), 1976 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: General (6 of 6), 1977 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Fifty Years of Atheism, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Autumn 1969 Series, 1969 September (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: The Soviet Union and Religion Today, 1969-1970 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Notes from Japan, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Far East, 1970 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Religion in the Contemporary World (1 of 2), 1970 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Religion in the Contemporary World (2 of 2), 1971 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Swedish Conference on Christianity and Communism, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (1 of 12), 1968, undated (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (2 of 12), 1970-1972 May (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (3 of 12), 1972 June-December (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (4 of 12), 1973 January-May (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (5 of 12), 1973 June-December (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (6 of 12), 1974 January-October (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (7 of 12), 1974 November-December (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (8 of 12), 1975 January-May (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (9 of 12), 1975 June-December (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (10 of 12), 1976 January-June (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (11 of 12), 1976 July-December (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Soviet Union (12 of 12), 1977 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Suppression and Renewal - The Russian Orthodox Church Today, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Events in Lithuania, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Alexander Solzhenitsyn - Defender of Faith, 1974 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Scripts: Radio Liberty: Case no. 345 - The Vilnius Samizdat Trial, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Transcript: Radio Liberty: Panel Discussion "The Future of Samizdat: Significance & Prospects", 1971 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Scripts: BBC World Service: General (1 of 3), 1966-1971 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Scripts: BBC World Service: General (2 of 3), 1972-1980 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Scripts: BBC World Service: General (3 of 3), 1983-2001 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Script: BBC World Service: The Coming of Christ-as Light Out of Darkness: Christmas Broadcast from Smolensk, 19 December 1999: Draft Script and Correspondence, 1998-2000 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Scripts: Norwegian Radio: From Death to Life: The Fall of Soviet Atheism, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Scripts: Rediffusion Television Limited: Children of the Revolution, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Scripts: Thames Television: Russian Witness, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Scripts: Thames Television Epilogue: Georgi Vins, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Scripts: Thames Television Epilogue: Dr Zviad Gamsakhurdia, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Scripts: Thames Television: No Vain Sacrifice?, 1981 April (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Notes: The History of Christianity In Russia: Lecture Course, 1958, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Notes: Kathryn W. Davis Lecture Series, Wellesley College, 1981 October-November (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Manuscript: Free Movement of Peoples: the Christian Church: International Interdoc Conference Paper, 1973 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Manuscript: To Set the Record Straight, 1989 October 10 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Manuscript: Religion and the Collapse of Soviet Communism: Boston University, 1991 December 13 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Manuscript: Religion and the Collapse of Soviet Communism: The Hebrew University of Jerusalem Conference Paper and Program, 1991-1992 (Box 22, Folder 16)
  - Manuscript: Religion and the Collapse of Soviet Communism: The Hugh Seton-Watson Memorial Lecture, 1992 April 29 (Box 22, Folder 17)
  - Manuscript: Goskontsert: Soviet Control of Music and Musicians: Great Britain-Russian Society Lecture, 2015 February 19 (Box 22, Folder 18)
  - Manuscript: 25 Years of Lithuanian Independence: a Personal View: Nottingham Lecture on Lithuania, 2015 March 15 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Manuscript: Ukrainian Consultation, Lambeth Palace, 2015 April 28 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - Manuscript: Religious Freedom for Ukraine:The Contribution of Keston College (1959-1989): Ukrainian Catholic University Lecture, L'viv, 2016 October 6 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - Manuscript: Plaque Dedication on the 50th Anniversary of Keston College Speech, 2019 June 20 (Box 22, Folder 22)
- Templeton Foundation Materials, 1984-2006, undated; 3
  The Templeton Foundation Materials Series include the 1984 Templeton Prize acceptance speech, correspondence between Michael Bourdeaux and Foundation officials, and print materials from the ensuing years. This series is in good condition.
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence: Congratulatory Cards (1 of 8), 1984 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (2 of 8), 1992 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (3 of 8), 1993 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (4 of 8), 1994 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (5 of 8), 1995 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (6 of 8), 1996, 1998, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (7 of 8), 2004 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Correspondence (8 of 8), 2005 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: The Templeton Prize Acceptance Speech: "The Poor who make many Rich: a Theology of Persecution", 1984 May 15 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Articles about the Templeton Prize Recipients, 1992-1999 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Print Materials (1 of 3), 1989-1996 (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Print Materials (2 of 3), 2001 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Templeton Foundation Materials: Print Materials (3 of 3), 2006 (Box 23, Folder 13)